So, hello everyone, welcome back to this video.
So in the previous video, we have worked with this this sign up route, right, this sign
up route.
Now in this video, we are going to work it with this login and log out routes, ok.
So remove this one, so similarly here we can make this function as async, ok.
And now what we are going to do is this is a login route, ok.
So what we are going to do is like we are going to take the email and password, ok.
So email and password through the request body.
So request dot body.
Now what we are going to do is we are going to implement a try in cache block.
So try and cache block and this cache block we are going to pass this error as argument
and now inside this try block, what we are going to do is just take one user so const
user equal to await user dot find one, so we are going to find the user through the email.
So we are going to use this function from the Mongoose and we are going to find that user
whether it exists or not.
So if it is existing, ok, if it is existing in that case what we are going to do is
sorry, if it is not existing, ok, we are going to first check it for the non existing user.
So res dot status, suppose for example when you are logging, ok, some user is logging
through the application and it passes that invalid credentials, ok.
So in that case res dot status 400.g send and we are just going to pass the message as message
invalid credentials credentials.
So invalid credentials and now we are going to check for the password.
So const is password equals to await we crypt dot compare, we are going to compare the
password, ok.
So whatever the user has typed a password, we are going to that to compare that password
so password, which with actual password so user dot password, right, we are going to
use this be crypt dot compare function.
So compare function is going to compare that password in the user password, whether it
is correct or not.
So we are going to check whether is password so is password is correct, ok.
So if the password is not correct in that case, we are going to just say that in the res
dot status 400 that it is a incorrect password, ok.
So dot g send, let us pass this message here and incorrect password, ok, so we are going
to save this.
Now after that, since we have checked all of that, whether that user exists in the database
or not and then we are going to check whether that password is correct or not, whatever
the user has typed, we are going to use this be crypt dot compare to compare the password
and the password which is stored in the database and we are going to add this marker.
Now after this, we are going to just attach us a digital token.
So what, how it is going to do is like we are going to use that token generation function
which we have written in the, in that file, where was token dot choose.
So we are going to generate a token and we are going to digitally sign it to the user.
So user dot underscore id and res.
So now it is generated and now after this we are going to do one more thing, we are going
to pass that status, ok.
So since we have a digitally signed in, so res dot status dot 200.
So 200 is a status cost which represents the, ok, like successful request, ok.
So res dot status 200 dot JSON and now in the JSON underscore id user, user dot underscore
id and comma, we are going to use this user name.
So user dot user name and the email user dot email, ok.
So now we have implemented this also and now whatever is remaining, we are going to implement.
So this cash block.
Since all the cash block what we are going to just write is simple console dot log statement
that error in login and simply we are going to send out the error dot message, ok, error
dot message.
So control as save this.
So basically the workflow is email password, we are going to pass it from like request.body,
we are going to get from the request.body, we are going to check whether the user exists
in the database or not, ok.
So we are applied checks for both user and password, we are going to check whether the password
which is typed by the user is matching the password which we have made in the signup request,
ok.
So in the signup request, it is already registered in the database, whatever the password
we have had there, ok.
So this peak creep.compare function is going to compare that and after this we are going
to send if that password doesn't exist, this RAS.status400.json message in correct
password and then we are going to distillize sign it like whenever the user logs in,
ok.
So whenever the user logs in, we are going to distillize sign 1,2,n and we are going to return
the status as 200, ok that user has signed incorrectly, otherwise in the cash block
we have, we are going to console log this error.
So error in the login in error dot message, ok.
So this is about the login and also RAS dot status 500, so status code 500 in case of error
and return that in the JSON format and let us pass that message, ok.
And today is an internal server, so internal, internal server error, ok.
So let us check this one, so we are going to also test this one route, so what we are
going to do is, now let us go here and make another request control, ok.
It is working quite slow, wait a second, yeah, go here and put this to post request, ok.
So HTTP, double slash local host, 5000 slash or slash login, ok.
So in the body we are going to just pass as a test data, ok.
So username, since in this one only to username is required, so let us check this whatever
we have taken here, so basically 51 minutes ago, so we are going to copy this one, ok.
Let us copy and we are going to paste it here and one other one, password add name
this as shan shan, ok.
So password, what do you think the expected output would be, would be, cancel, let us check
this one, invalid credentials, why, invalid credentials because see, we have the password
length which is smaller than 6, that is why.
So let us take another one, so we have had request write, so we can take this email and
then we are going to just copy paste, wait, wait a second, wait a second, here we have
taken this one second, let us go to that controller.js we are going to take what, so
in this one we are taking the email and password, ok.
So just copy both of this field here, so copy and then go here and then just paste it
like this, now if you just said this, so as you can see that this is correctly created,
so 200, ok.
So request was successful, the server has responded as required and cookies is also made
like this J2 to 3 token as you can see here and header is also created and test results
only, so that is how this login is logged in, it is also working correctly, so now let us
work on our logout request, so in the logout what we will do is, we will just set all
the, like clear all the values, ok.
So we are going to just clear all the values in case of the logout, so we are just going
to set the key value, so reas.cokey, so whatever the cookie that has been set in the local
storage, we will just go there and we will just assign it as empty value and we are going
to just change the max h2 like 0, why?
Because once we click on the logout button, we are just saying that make this as max h
as 0 and we are just going to remove the token or the token is expired, ok.
And again for this one, we are going to just use that reas.state as 200, so request was
successful.json and we are going to pass the message, we are going to pass the message
as logged out successfully, so logged out successfully, so you can test this route as
well, so it would be correctly working, so we can see in the next video, but one more practice,
ok.
Since in the above videos, we are trying the try and cache block, ok.
So wrap this one in the try block, ok, try and cache block, so put this here and cache
block error, put this reas and restart status to the cache block, ok, so cache block and
please remove this one, 1 second, so console.log error in logout, ok, so error.message,
and now reas.stitas 500.json message.
And then we can test this route as well, it will be working correctly as expected, go to
the disposed one and just change it to the logout and it will be working fine.
So see you in the next video.